I'm Alex Villarreal with the VOA Special English Education Report.
Songs teach language. Consider a song like Tom's Diner by Suzanne Vega. An American teaching
English overseas once told us that students love that song. Recently, we asked people on
the Special English Facebook page to suggest other songs that English learners might like.
Noemi Nito wrote, I'm one of those English students who love Tom's Diner. I started
learning English with lemon tree by Fools Garden. Another favorite is truly madly
deeply by Savage Garden. Another person, Asi Tambunan, suggested the song God Only
Knows by Orianti. Yogi Yako wrote that Abba's songs from Sweden are perfect for class
work. Other good songs for learning English are songs by the Beatles and John Lennon as
well as Louis Armstrong's wonderful world. Paul Cifuentes says Bob Marley's songs are
amazing for teaching. Another teacher, Joseph Deca, says songs by Johnny Cash have always
worked in his classroom. He says his students can hear the words, plus the songs often
have stories. He also likes We Will Rock You by Queen and Beautiful Girls by Sean Kingston.
He says young children love sea is for cookie by cookie monster from the TV show Sesame Street.
Nina John Smith suggested these songs. It's My Life and we weren't born to follow by Bon Jovi.
Also nothing else matters by Metallica.
Aurelio Lorenzo Costagu-Smow says he began to like English after his teacher played the West
Life Song. I have a dream. He wrote that was eight years ago. I was in the seventh grade.
And from that day on, my dream of improving my English skills became attached in my mind.
Teachers can use this song to convey the message to their students that they should have their
own dream for the future. Aurelio's story was no surprise to another commenter, Katja Kovenko.
She especially likes songs by Michael Jackson and Queen. She wrote,
When you listen to your favorite songs, you feel emotionally high and it moves you to action.
For VOA Special English, I'm Alex Villareal. Do you have any favorite songs for learning English?
You can share other music suggestions for English learners at our website.
VOASpecialEnglish.com or on Facebook at VOA Learning English. We are also on Twitter and iTunes.